

With over three years of experience in developing innovative IoT, data and digitalization solutions, I have extensive know-how. I have mastered waterfall model, agile methods and the DevOps process to successfully implement projects. I attach great importance to developing together

# Michael Bieri

Grotweg 23
2543 Lengnau BE
+41 77 413 08 39
michael.bieri@hotmail.com
13.03.1992







### Work Experience

07/2024 - 10/2024	Career break Relocation, travel and continuing education
03/2021 - 06/2024	Junior Electro Engineer LAUFEN Bathrooms AG, Laufen Development and management of soft- and hardware projects with focus on requirement engineering
09/2018 - 02/2021	Junior Project Manager Amstein + Walthert Basel AG, Basel Engineering in building technology/automation
07/2018 - 09/2018	Engineering Internship Kappeler Infra Consult AG, Laufen
11/2013 - 07/2014	Workshop and Construction Internship F. Hoffmann-La-Roche AG, Basel
11/2010 - 05/2011	<b>Trust Internship</b> TVR Treuhand GmbH, Basel
09/2009 - 10/2009	Bank Internship WIR Bank, Basel

## Soft Skills

About Me

REQUIREMENT ENGINEERING

with the company, using new technologies and implementing innovative digitalization products.



AGILE PROJECTMANAGEMENT



**CLASSIC PROJECTMANAGEMENT** 



ANALYTICAL THINKING



**STATISTICS** 



DATA SCIENCE



**DATA ANALYSIS** 



- Professional Scrum Master II
- Databricks Certified Data Engineer Associate
- Microsoft Fundamentals in Azure, Power Platform, MS365



#### Education

02/2024 - 08/2024	<b>CAS Data Science Fundamentals</b> Swiss Distance University of Applied Sciences FFHS
09/2019 - 04/2022	MAS Automation Management University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
09/2014 - 05/2018	BSc Energy- and Environment Technology University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
08/2011 - 08/2012	<b>Technical High School Diploma</b> Vocational training center BL, Liestal
08/2007 - 08/2010	Business Diploma Business school kvBL, Reinach BL



### Languages

German	Mother tongue	
Fnglish	C1	

French B2